Alan Medina Silva

Application Developer

Contact

Address

Zapopan, JAL, 45130

Phone

331 865 4154

E-mail

alanmedina437@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alan-medina-511277118/

Skills

Programming

React JS

REST

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Integration

Database Management (MySql, Sql Server, MongoDB)

.Net development

API design knowledge

PHP development

Agile Workflow

Larav<u>el</u>

I'm a software developer with 4 years of experience, I've done work for agencies, artists, companies, and collaborated with talented people to create digital products for both business and consumer use. I'm quietly confident, naturally curious, well-organized and customer-focused with proven skills in project management and team leadership.

Work History

2019-10 -Current

Support Engineer

Softtek, Guadalajara, Jalisco

Front end Developer and SharePoint Support Member

- I worked on the design and development of a SharePoint application that helps all the users worldwide to classify and add security validations to files on the SharePoint platform using modern web technologies like ReactJS(SPFX) and serverless functions with azure.
- I Provide SharePoint support for all the users of the company resolving tickets.
- Collaborated with outside departments to implement system-wide improvements.
- Broke down and evaluated user problems, using test scripts, personal expertise and probing questions.

2016-07 -Current

Web Developer

IlemiOnline, Guadalajara, Jalisco

Web developer

- I worked on the design, development and implementation of multiple kind of website, such as blogs, e commerce and business pages. and also took part on the SEO management.
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement.
- Determined coding requirements for site creation, including e-commerce capability, security and specialized scripts.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.

2017-08 - **Application Developer**

HTML

CSS

Javscript (jQuery)

React Native

Git

Azure Cloud

Firebase

Java

Languages

English (PET – B2 Level Cambridge Certification 2017) 2019-10

Flex, Zapopan, Jalisco

Full Stack Developer and SharePoint Business Analyst and Developer of applications that were used worldwide.

- I coordinated the implementation of ReactJS as a development tool for all the complex incoming projects.
- I helped the support team with technical SharePoint issues that involved custom code.
- Along with team we won a third place prize for best innovation project using Office 365 Bots API to automatize user's knowledge base interaction.
- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.

Education

2013-08 -2017-07

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science Engineering

Universidad Autonoma De Sinaloa - Mazatlan, Sinaloa Graduated in Third place on grade-point averages at state level

Portfolio

advenculture.com
tropigasgt.com
ismaeldeanda3.com
totte.com.mx
rainartstudio.com
christoph-dahlhausen.de
laestaciongallery.com
insectodofumigaciones.com
monbaby.com.mx
pachilifecoach.com
encuestasamedida.com
manasse.com.mx
potenzamexico.com
clinicaaltamira.com

fernandorascon.com.mx alas-de-amor.com